Tompkins Cortland Labor Coalition Records 6185
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- New York State Dept. of Labor -- Health and Safety Grant, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Correspondence, applications and newspaper articles. Meeting agendas and notes, and training material.
- New York State Dept. of Labor -- Health and Safety Grant, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Correspondence and contract signature sheet from 1988-1991.
- New York State Dept. of Labor -- Local Initiatives, 1989-1992 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Correspondence and "Detail Reimbursement Request" forms.
- New York State Dept. of Labor -- Quarterly Reports, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Correspondence, reports, paperwork, budget papers.
- New York State Dept. of Labor -- Quarterly Reports, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- New York State Dept. of Labor -- Quarterly Reports, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- New York State Dept. of Labor -- Quarterly Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- New York State Dept. of Labor -- Quarterly Reports, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- New York State Dept. of Labor -- Quarterly Reports, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- New York State Employment Relations Board (NYSERB), 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  Booklet about NYSERB, petition for investigation and certification of representatives pursuant to Section 705, correspondence, copy of New York State Employment Relations Act.
- New York State United Teachers (Box 5, Folder 23)
  Copies of newsletter "For Your Health/Safety"
- News Clippings, 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Photos, newspaper clippings of union and labor topics that made local headlines and impacted local unions in the 1980's and 1990's
- News Releases and Press Conferences -- TCLC, 1986-1994 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Press releases, correspondence
- Newsletter, Newspaper Training, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Leaflets That Work-- training pamphlet for writing newspaper ads/articles, union newspapers and leaflets (a seminar pamphlet from NYS School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Extension Division)
- Nursing Home Grant, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Copy of the grant proposal & correspondence
- OSHTEP (Occupational Safety and Health Training Education Program) -- Miscellaneous, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, meeting notes, membership lists, and meeting agendas, and newspaper articles.
- Organizing Information and Leads, 1977-1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  "Dynamics of Organizing" by Shel Trapp, Direct Action Organizing papers, labor organizing information
- Participatory OSH Education, 1989-1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Newspaper articles, several papers and articles written about Occupational Health & Safety training, workshop folder from "Participatory Occupational Health Education from Hunter Center for Occupational & Environmental Health.
- Pension, 1991-1997 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Several pamphlets offering information on pensions.
- PERB/Taylor Law, 1989-1997 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  List/price list of publications by PERB (Public Employment Relations Board), notes, correspondence, 2 PERB publications -- "The Taylor Law: 1989-1990" and "What is the Taylor Law"
- PESH (NYS Public Employee Safety and Health), 1984-2000 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Pamphlets by PESH - "Consultation Assistance Available to Public Employees", "Inspection of Places of Public Employment", "Recording and Reporting Public Employees' Occupational", "Public Employee Safety and Health Act", "Voices of the Rank and File PESH Inspectors", copy of NYS Dept of Labor Safety Hazard report sheet, correspondence.
- Plant Closings, 1984-1994 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Newspaper clippings, correspondence, NCR Corporation 1987 Annual report, papers written on "Early Warning" for plant closings - Books include --"He's Staying the Course", "County Business Patters", "Early Warning Manual Against Plant Closings", "West Side Jobs Retention Network", "What's Happening to Your Job?"
- Plant Closings -- Legislation, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Information on "The Warn Act", "Your Right to be Warned" (an UAW manual), Highlights of the 1988 Plant Closing Law, correspondence
- Plant Closings Publications, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Various books and manuals published dealing with plant closing,articles, Social Cost Analysis of (Chrysler Auto Assembly Plant, Kenosha, Wisconsin), (Trico Plants in Buffalo, NY), Bethlehem Steel Impact Study, Midwest Center for Labor Research, 1987-1988 Annual report
- Plant Closings Publications (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Playground safety (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Articles and news clippings
- Policy/Legislation, 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Paper by OCAW (Oil, Chemical, and Atomic Workers International Union), publications of the US General Accounting Office, "Occupational Safety & Health: Options for Improving Safety...
- Public Employee Relations Law -- Taylor Law --, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  NYSTaylor Law booklet, Rules of Procedure, "What is the Taylor Law", select publications by Public Employee Relations Board (PERB)
- Public Sector, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  Correspondence, advertisements for rallys
- A. Philip Randolph -- Exhibit, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  Correspondence and pamphlets with information about A. Philip Randolph and the exhibit.Newspaper articles.
- Resolutions, 1988-1994 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  Correspondence on local resolutions that TCLC had a role in."Labor Coalition Statement on Development and the Proposed Moratorium"
- Resource lists (Box 6, Folder 21)
  List of resources to contact for Occupational Safety and Health Issues
- Resources, 1984-2001 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  Publication and video catalogs from The Labor Insitute; California Working Group, Inc.; Cornell University, Chemical Hazard Information Program; Labor Occupational Health Program; OSHA
- R.E.S.P.E.C.T. for Injured Workers (Box 6, Folder 23)
  Information sheets and correspondence.
- Right to know, 1981-1993 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  Workshop folder from " The Right to Know Law: What You Should Know About Toxic Substances", "The Trainer's Guide to New Jersey's Right to Know Law", articles and pamphlets about the Right to Know Law.
- Saulsbury Fire Apparatus -- Organizing Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Safety information, organizing information, meeting announcements, correspondence, Employee Handbook.
- Scholarship Committee, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  TCLC Worker's Compensation Program Course & Scholarship Applications, correspondence, Pre-Registration & Course Scholarship results
- Schools (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Schools Environmental safety information
- Small Business, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Pamphlets & booklets on Occupational Health & Safety for Small Businesses.
- Smith Corona Machine (SCM) Layoffs, 1983-1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Layoffs Executive Summary done by TCLC, photos, newspaper clippings, survey and survey answers of SCM employees, legal papers for employees who sued SCM, correspondence to employees, SCM, TCLC, newspapers
- Smith Corona Machine (SCM) Layoffs/Plant shutdown, 1990-2000 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Social Security - Disability, 1989-1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Pamphlets, newspaper clippings
- Solidarity Committee, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Solidarity Committee "Solidarity Notes" official publication of the Solidarity Committee, draft of the by-laws, correspondence.
- Songs -- Music -- Chants (Box 7, Folder 9)
  UAW song booklet, song sheets, music sheets, labor chants, slogan sheets.
- Spanish materials (Box 7, Folder 10)
  Copies of "NCOSH" in Spanish, handbooks and information sheets
- Staff Reports -- TCLC, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  Reports to the Labor Coalition from each Committee about their work from month to month. (Coalition, City Funding, Health and Safety Funding) -- Summary of history of TCLC.
- Supporter lists, phone sheets (Box 7, Folder 12)
  Mail label lists, blank mailing forms, phone caller "rap" sheet
- Sweden (Box 7, Folder 13)
  Articles and booklets on Sweden's Occupational Health & Safety
- TCLC -- Health and Safety Advisory Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  Notes and correspondence.
- Tenants/Rights Housing Laws, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  Handbooks for mobile home tenants rights and for renters rights, guide to NYS Fair Housing Laws against housing discrimination.
- Tompkins County Public Library -- Support Staff Association, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  Correspondence about mediation regarding wages at the library.
- Tompkins County Residents Job Policy, 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  Copy of Jobs Policy, correspondence to various Unions and representatives to encourage their support of the Jobs Policy.
- Trade Union Women's Conference, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  Trade Union Women's Conference Conference packet.
- Treasurers Information -- Monthly, 1984-1991 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  Financial statements, copies of budget figures
- Union Neighborhood Assistance Corp. (UNAC), 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  Newspaper and magazine articles, job descriptions, budget information.Explanation of who UNAC is and what they do.
- Whistleblower, 1991-1998 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  Pamphlets, articles, newspaper clippings about Whistleblowers, zeroxes of law, copy of "The Patient Safety and Health Care Whistleblower Protection Act".
- Women & OSH (Box 7, Folder 22)
  Correspondence and articles about women's health and safety.
- Women Employees (Box 7, Folder 23)
  Pamphlets, memos and educational material on women in the workforce.
- Womens Committee, 1991-1995 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  Photos, pamphlets, phone list for attendees, evaluation form, sign up sheet for events, attendance sheets, mailing label sheets, registration list.
- Womens Conference, 1991-1993 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  Correspondence and notes, roster list, agendas, handouts.
- Women's Day, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  Central New York Women's Institute for Leadership Development - Pre- Conference Survey - (names/addresses etc.), Conference packet, programs for 1990 & 1991 Int'l. Women's Day Program, pamphlets, correspondence, button.
- Women's Leadership Development Conference, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  Women's Leadership Development ConferenceCorrespondence, Labor Coalition Women's Committee Contact List, invitation, reservations, packet for conference.
- Workers Compensation -- Research and Background (Box 7, Folder 28)
  Pamphlets, booklets, newspaper articles and correspondence about workers compensation cases.
- Workers Compensation -- Research and Background, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Pamphlets, booklets, newspaper articles about workers compensation cases.
- Workers Compensation Material, 1997-1999 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  Newspaper clippings, flyers, correspondence, copies of "Workers' Comp: Myths & Realities", pamphlets, copies of "CWIP (The Center on Worker Injury Policy, Inc.)
- Workers Compensation Material, 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Workers Compensation Material, 1988-1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  Newspaper clippings, flyers, correspondence, handouts
- Workers Compensation Material (Box 8, Folder 5)
  Undated material, flyers, booklets, newspaper clippings, forms
- Workers' Compensation Workshops, 1991-1994 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  New York State Workers' Compensation Handbook, Application for License to appear on behalf of claimants, reservation stubs, rules and procedures of New York State Workers' Compensation Board, proposed syllabus, correspondence, workshop announcements, sign-in sheets, infromation sheets, forrms, etc.
- Workers Memorial Day, 1998-2002 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  Correspondence, occupational fatality reports, activity flyers, announcements, organizational material, newspaper clippings, Massachusetts workplace report on fatalities.
- Workers Memorial Day, 1996-1998 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  Booklet, flyers, Occupational Health & Safety newsletter, correspondence, UAW Represented Workplaces, fatalities list, AFL-CIO fact sheet.
- Workers Memorial Day, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  Photos, newspaper clippings, flyers, correspondence, agenda, pamphlets, posters
- Workers Memorial Day, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  Photos, newspaper clippings, flyers, correspondence, Workers Memorial Day kit, copy of Proclamation, press releases.
- Workers Memorial Day, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  Flyers, information sheets, copy of Proclamation, newspaper clippings, posters, correspondence, labor songs, agendas, photos & negatives, "Labor Alert", press releases.
- Working Poor "The Working Poor" by David Gordon. News articles and information items on current workforces., 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  "The Working Poor" by David Gordon. News articles and information items on current workforces.
- Working Press Articles (Box 8, Folder 13)
  Newspaper clippings, magazine articles, correspondence, ideas for future/past articles
- Working Press -- Miscellaneous, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  Copies of ideas for articles. Correspondence and copies of articles.
- Working Press -- Solidarity Issue --, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  Labor Day 1995. Working Press -- Solidarity Issue -- Labor Day 1995Correspondence and article ideas, also copies of finished articles.
- Workshop -- Air Quality, 1989-1998 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Workshop -- Air Quality Handouts, correspondence, conference material
- Workshop -- Air Quality, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  Workshop -- Air Quality pamphlets and booklets from the conferences
- Workshop -- Asbestos, 1984-1989 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  Informational material and handouts
- Workshop -- Asbestos, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  Booklets from workshops
- Workshop -- Back clinics, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Information on back injuries and on clinics offered
- Workshop -- Confined Space training, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  Space training Handouts, correspondence
- Workshop -- Evaluation sheets, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  Examples of evaluation sheets used, and instructions on how to create new ones
- Workshop -- Family & Medical Leave Act (Box 9, Folder 8)
  Newspaper articles, information material, correspondence
- Workshop -- Hazard Materials Communication, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  Handouts, correspondence
- Workshop -- Infection control, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  Workshop folder with all the workshop materials and handouts
- Workshop -- Lead, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  Handouts, pamphlets, correspondence
- Workshop -- Machining Fluid Hazards, 1993-2003 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  Handouts, information sheets, correspondence
- Workshop -- Office Space Hazards, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  Handouts, infromation sheets, correspondence
- Workshop -- Repetitive Injury, 1996-1999 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  Handouts, correspondence, workshop information
- Workshop -- Reproductive Health, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  Correspondence, information sheets, workshop sheets
- Workshop -- SEIU Health & Safety, 1993-1998 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  Correspondence and handouts
- Workshop -- Womens Health & Safety (Box 9, Folder 17)
  Conference booklet & handouts
- Workshop -- Workmens' Compensation, 1991-2003 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  Correspondence, training material, handouts
- Workshop -- Workplace Safety, 1989-1992 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  Workplace Safety handouts, correspondence
- Newsletter - FYI - Health Care Workers, 1998-2000 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  Copies of newsletters published.
- Newsletter - FYI -- Health Care Workers, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  Current research notes for newsletter.
- Newsletter - FYI -- Health Care Workers-, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  Copy of newsletter, research articles, notes, correspondence, and newspaper clippings
- Newsletter -- FYI -- Index, 1990-1994 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  Index for newsletter, list of videos in Labor Coalition Resource Center.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - Issues, 1990-2001 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  Copies of newsletters pubilshed (not complete)
- Newsletter -- FYI - Office Workers - Issues - Current, 1996-2001 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  Newspaper clippings about workplace issues, correspondence, copies of FYI, Int'l. Federation for Journalists, Communique, The Source: Indoor Air Quality and Your Schools, Canary News, many articles from other publications relating to workplace issues and injuries used as research for the newsletter.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - Spring 2001 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  Copy of newsletter, research articles, correspondence and newspaper clippings.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - Spring 2000 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  Copy of newsletter, research articles, notes, correspondence and newspaper clippings.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - Summer 2000 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  Copy of newsletter, research articles, notes, correspondence, and newspaper clippings.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - Fall 2000 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  Copy of newsletter, research articles, notes and correspondence.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - Winter 1999 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - Fall 1999 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  Copy of newsletter, research correspondence, notes and newspaper clippings.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - March 1999 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - May 1999 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  Copies of newsletter, research correspondence and notes, newspaper clippings.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - June 1999 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - March 1998 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  Copy of newsletter, newspaper clippings and research notes.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - June 1998 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  Copy of newsletter, research notes and correspondence.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - September 1998 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  Copy of newsletter, mailing list, newspaper clippings, research notes and articles.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - November 1998 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  Copy of newsletter, research correspondence and notes. "Double Jeaopardy: Caseworkers at Risk: Helping at Risk Kids".
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - September 1997 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  Copy of newsletter, notes and articles for research.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - December 1997 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  Copy of newsletter, correspondence, newspaper clippings, research notes.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - March 1996 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  Copy of newsletter, notes, newspaper clippings, Women in Public Service newsletter, research notes.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - June 1996 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  Copy of newsletter, articles, notes and research information.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - December 1996 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  Copy of newsletter, articles and notes used for research of this issue.
- Newsletter - FYI - Office Workers - June 1995 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  Copy of newsletter, correspondence and articles, notes on workers' comp., workplace violence, and indoor air quality, used for research.
- Newsletter - FYI - School Employees - Issues, 1994-1999 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  Copies of issues of newsletter (not complete)
- Newsletter - FYI - School Employees - Current, 1989-1994 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  Articles and correspondence about dagers in and around school buildings, information used for research on latest newsletter.
- Newsletter - FYI - School Employees - March 1999 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  Copy of newsletter, research correspondence and literature, "Worker vs. Worker", newspaper clippings.
- Newsletter - FYI - School Employees - February 1998 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  Copy of newsletter, correspondence, newspaper clippings, research articles.
- Newsletter - FYI - School Employees - May 1998 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  Research notes, "Mortality by Occupation, Industry, and Cause of Death", used for research.
- Newsletter - FYI - School Employees - November 1997 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  Copy of newsletter, articles, newspaper clippings, notes and correspondence.
- Newsletter - FYI - School Employees - April 1996 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  Copy of newsletter, articles, notes used to research topics in this issue.
- Newsletter - FYI - School Employees - September 1996 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  Correspondence, articles, research notes, newspaper clippings used for researching this issue. Copy of newsletter.
- Newsletter - FYI - School Employees - February 1995 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  Copy of newsletter, "Teachers Are Too Often Victims", articles used for research.
- Newsletter - FYI - School Employees - May 1995 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  "Indoor Air Quality: A Local Case Study", correspondence and articles used in researching this issue.
- Newsletter - FYI - School Employees - October 1995 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  Copy of newsletter, newspaper clippings, research notes.
- Newsletter - FYI - Sexual Harassment, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  Correspondence and articles used for researching this topic.
- Newsletter - FYI - Support Letters, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  E-mails and correspondence in support of the publishing of this newsletter, copy of FYI readers survey.
- Newsletter - FYI - VDT Dangers, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  Correspondence and articles used to research this topic, and the topics of Carpal Tunnel, Electro-Magnetic Exposure and Vision problems.
- Health & Safety -- Activist List (Box 10, Folder 34)
  Names and addresses of health & safety activists.
- Health & Safety -- Bulletin (Box 10, Folder 35)
  Copies of TCLC "Health & Safety Bulletin", correspondence and memo on Right to Know Training.
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Contract Languages, 1983-2001 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  Correspondence, articles, newsletters, sample of contract language mostly dealing with collective bargaining language for contracts - contract language for health and safety issues, VDT use, pamphlets on health and safety programs.
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Controlling Hazards, 1991-1995 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  Copy of The Safety Link, news articles and information collected on chemical hazards in the workplace.
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Educating the membership, 1987-1993 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  Memos, news items on safety issues, newspaper clippings.
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Getting help, 1985-1997 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  Magazine articles, memos, UAW information sheets, correspondence, sample correspondence, copy of "Right to Know Complaint Form".Booklets - "It Takes More Than Housecalls", by Kate Bronfenbrenner (Director of Labor Education Research, NYSSI&LR), "Numbers That Count", by AFL-CIO, "Steward Manual", by CSEA, "Health and Safety for Inside Strategies", Organizing for Health and Safety" by Int'l. Chemical Workers Union, "How to Make Your Job Healthier" by NJ Dept. of Health, "Playing Industrial Hygiene to Win".
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Getting help (Box 10, Folder 40)
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Getting help - Physicians, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  Tip sheet from Central New York Council on Occupational Safety & Health (CNYCOSH), for maintaining a daily health log. Tip sheet on what to tell your doctor, pamphlets "Workplace Health Programs" and "Occupational Health Hazards".
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- General information, 1984-1999 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  Newspaper clippings, magazine articles, memos, handwritten notes all used in gathering information on health and safety in the workplace."UNMET NEEDS", a paper put out by the National Safety Workplace Institute, "Building Solidarity in the Local Union" by Cornell University, NYS School of Industrial & Labor Relations, Extension Division.
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Getting information, 1983-1991 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  Getting information Surveys, articles, memos, booklets, UAW Training materials about chemical hazards, training memos on industrial hygiene, daily health logs, tracking hazards, reporting hazards, examples of employee forms, "How to Look at Your Plant", "Understanding Toxic Substances", "A Brief Guide to Record - Keeping Requirments for Occupational Injuries and Illnesses".
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- work related subjects, 1984-1989 (Box 11, Folder 1)